Okay.
>> I'm not lying. I wouldn't. So, how we
doing?
>> Good. [snorts] Um,
so I mean, overall, I'd say kind of
continuation of some of the things we've
talked about in the offseason. You know,
just building a tough, smart, physical
team. uh players that have the right
mindset, right mentality. Um so as far
as just trades, positioning,
I'd say the the first pick with with
Kaden, kind of moving a couple slots,
repositioning kind of like we did with
Kalin or K. Yeah, Kalin, uh you know, we
felt McDonald was probably the best run
defender in the draft. Um had a really
productive season, you know, defensive
tackle that was involved in 60 tackles
or 60 plus tackles, whatever it is. Um
it's pretty impressive. Um, and we like
the first unanimous defensive tackle,
unanimous all-American defensive tackle
in the history of Ohio State's program.
I mean, like they've had a few decent
players there. So, um, it's a good kid,
young kid. I mean, played the season,
was 20 years old. I mean, just turned
21. So, um, you know, I Matt Patricia
did a really good job with him this
year. Got the most out of him. Um, guy
was a good player. You know, spent a lot
of time with him. So, feel our program
will be good good fit. He'll be a good
fit for our program. our program will
kind of be a good fit for him. But you
know he does well and he does it well.
So um you know that was him and then uh
you know at 59. So we had multiple
discussions. We were kind of potentially
trading a pick, moving it, had a few
deals in place and those fell apart. So
we had a couple guys that we were
talking about picking. Um and then you
know Marlin was one of them. I would say
for us Marlin like was kind of a
no-brainer. Um, this is a player we
really liked. Um, his story, I mean, you
guys will get, if you haven't talked to
him, like his story is really
impressive. Like, the fact that he's
even here having this discussion really
speaks to who he is, his maturity, his
intelligence, his toughness. I mean, he
could have sat out the bowl game,
basically told his coach and, you know,
everybody else, his agents,
representatives, like, I'm playing. I
mean, kind of like what Kamari did the
year that he came out um, you know, with
Georgia. So, good size, runs well. I
mean, 6'5, 250, runs 46. Um, you know,
I'd say his best football is probably in
front of him, but type of player that
has the right mentality, has the right
mindset, good work ethic, really smart.
I'm sure we'll be playing in Germany
here, you know, one of these
international games. So, get your
passport ready at some point. Um, but
good football player. Um, who we visited
with at the combine. um really after the
combine like we were kind of done with
him as far as the person. I mean cuz
there really wasn't much more there that
we needed to talk about. So um you know
he was a player that we liked um we
liked him from the beginning of the
process um to drafting him which is you
know why we picked him. Um and then with
so we kind of repositioned uh the picks
there a little bit. So we flipped 91 for
117 I think or whatever it was part of
the Vegas trade. Um we're picking 106
117. So the players that we're talking
about tomorrow, it's the same players
that we would talk about at 91. So when
you look up there at the names, like we
would have picked one of the guys at 91
that still on the board that we're
probably going to talk about tomorrow.
So that trade similar to to the Ruters
trade, it was more about just
repositioning the picks because we
really didn't give anything up other
than slots. So then that's kind of how
we view it. Um so we got a few picks
tomorrow to kind of play around with. Um
we'll see how it goes there. um in the
morning. I mean, you know, we're what,
five or six picks out and then we have
117, then we have the one in the fifth,
don't we have the sixth, and then we
have the seventh round pick. So, we'll
see how it all kind of manifests itself
tomorrow and comes together. So, take
some questions.
>> Do you um with Kaden um McDonald, were
y'all surprised that he was kind of
dropping down? And did that factor in at
all to why you all wanted to trade up?
>> No. I mean, look, I think sometimes
everybody gets this like, you know, you
trade it up. I mean, you move two spots.
I mean, you're not really doing
anything. You're just trying to make
sure you get the football player. So, we
like the player. Look, if a player
falls, like we can't control any of
that. So, good player. We do the
evaluation. However, we get him in the
building, we get him in the building,
we'll pick him. Um, again, visit with
him. Brought him in the building. He was
here at NRG. Had a good visit with them.
Kind of continued in the process. Did a
lot of work on him. Have a lot of
respect for Coach Day and his program.
We have a lot of people at Ohio State
that we know, I'd say, in a pretty deep
level. um whether it's coaching staff,
you know, coach Patricia, Coach Day have
some folks on the strength staff, they
have some people on the training staff,
you know, Nate Abner was involved in the
program a little bit this year who, you
know, I was with Nate um in New England
there for a little bit. So, when you
have people like that, when they tell
you something, okay, what they're
telling you, you can probably trust. So,
to have that type of relationship and be
able to have the information kind of
solidified what we thought and where we
think the player is. Um, so, um, yeah, I
mean, he was a player that we liked
again, like we felt he was like the best
run stopping defensive tackle in the
draft. So, all right. Well, then let's
if we have an opportunity to add that
player, then let's go ahead and add him
to the team, which is what we did.
>> I think that's why I was saying like,
are you surprised cuz obviously you
loved him that he was like falling a
little bit.
>> Again, we can't control any of that.
Like, it's not up to us. So, if a
player's available, so we'll look at
what our options are. Um we had a few
players um at 38 and 36 whatever it was
probably like two or three guys like all
right if we have a chance to pick one of
these guys all right let's go ahead and
pick them and then you know it's well we
made the pick that we did
>> when it comes to McDonald there's more
ahead of him in terms of pass rushing we
saw a lot of run stopping from him and
sometimes he gets to the quarterback do
you think there's more ahead of him as
he refineses and continues to be around
your coaches
>> yeah we'll see I think the big thing you
got to play to your strengths so what a
player does well let let's accentuate
the strengths and then if a guy has an
area he can improve then we'll see if we
can get him to improve. I think
sometimes it's even a player has a
perception. Well, I want to be able to
do this. Well, okay, look, you're 6'3",
330 pounds. The best thing you do is
play strong at the point of attack. So,
your pass rush is probably going to be a
little bit different than, you know,
Deno Autry or somebody else that's
rushing inside there. So, you have to
play to your strengths. And then our
coaches, I mean, look, we got the best
defensive coaching staff in the league
and probably got the best defensive line
coach in the league and Rod and Coach
Oak. So, we're going to figure out a way
to get the player to play within our
system and in our scheme and try to
figure out like how we can utilize his
strengths and try to improve the areas
that we feel it needs to improve.
>> Follow up. When you think about the
overall defensive line, where you're at
right now with the edges that you have
and having the dackle rotation, how are
you feeling about the defensive line
overall that you've at right now?
>> Yeah, we'll see. I feel we'll have a
competitive defensive line and each week
it's going to change relative to who the
opponent is. So the bottom line in this
league like you got to be able to stop
the run, you got to be able to take the
ball away and you got to keep points off
the scoreboard. So that's what defensive
football is about. So however you do
that, like that's ultimately your
responsibility.
>> From a football standpoint, um you guys
since the Miko's been Miko's been here
at the defensive tackle spot, most of
them kind of range around 300 lb, a
little bit higher, a little bit lower.
Obviously McDonald's closer to 330. Um,
how much do you think that body type can
potentially unlock a different type of
approach that you guys may want to do?
Um, in terms of using a bigger body um,
you know, in a one tag, zero tag, things
that I need to do.
>> Yeah, I think well Demo and I have
talked continuously. There's a place for
that player in this front. I think
there's a perception of, well, he just,
you know, want a bunch of guys that just
like sprint off the ball and, you know,
don't have enough playing strength and
all that. Well, in the end, you got to
be able to play strong at the point of
attack. So, you're going to have to I
mean, Foley is a good example. Like
Foley, you know, whatever size he was,
him and Kaden McDonald are about not the
same size, but pretty close. So, there's
a place for that player on the inside
part of the defense, especially on early
downs. And then how to utilize that
player in, let's say, known passing
situations or on third down. Maybe
there's another option or maybe there's
a situation that you can create a
matchup with that player. So, we've
talked extensively that there's a place
for that type of player, that body body
type in in this system, and we don't
want to cast a player aside because he
maybe quote unquote doesn't fit the
profile. So, um, and I think that's the
beauty of our like defense and De Mo is
constantly looking for ways to evolve
and we're just not so beholden to, well,
this is the way it was three or four
years ago. I mean, our defense has
evolved, our team has evolved, and we
need to continue to evolve as a team and
as an organization. And so, to your
question, I think sometimes it's like,
well, does a player like this fit in
this front? The answer is absolutely
yes.
>> In Marlon Klein's case, because his his
maturation, he hadn't played a whole lot
of football compared to speak to a kid
coming from the US. Is that does that
did that pose any issues with y'all as
far as the amount of football he's been
played up until this point or you just
looking at a upside with him?
>> Yeah, not necessarily. I mean, you have
players with varied backgrounds, you
have some players that have been really
successful in this league who didn't
even play college football and you know
some people they only played high school
football. Marlin at least played even
though he grew up maybe not I want to
say football is foreign to him but he
wasn't thinking about playing probably
in the NFL when he was growing up in
Germany and then he came to the states
and then his career kind of evolved and
grew and he spent three or four years
however many years it was at Michigan
which has a good program and they had a
pretty good track record of tight ends
over the course of however many last
years I mean between schoonmaker Coulson
last year I mean they've had a number of
I'd say good players at that position um
he played behind some pretty good
players. I had his opportunity here this
year. Took advantage of his opportunity.
Um I'd say they were definitely more of
a running offense. So, you know, can he
improve and grow? I think he definitely
has the mentality and the mindset to
take coaching. He understands football.
He understands concepts. So, what you're
looking is the player have the
willingness and the drive to actually
work to improve. And I would say in
Marlin's case, it certainly appears that
way. Now, what that actually looks like,
we'll find out here as we go.
>> You mentioned mentioned having a couple
of deals in place. Were y'all trying to
move down at that at 59 at that point?
>> We we're looking at both. I mean, I
think this draft is kind of emblematic
of who we are with. We looked up. We had
opportunities to go up. I mean, I think
when we walked in a draft room, I think
we put like 10 boxes on the board. Like
we had a hey, here's the trade down
group. Here's the trade up group. All
right. What's real? What's not? I mean,
we probably talked to I don't want to
say half the league, we probably talked
to half the league here, you know, over
the course of the day, what's your
appetite for moving up? All right, got
it. All right, if we want to move up,
what would that look like? All right, if
we let's say we don't pick at 38 and we
end up moving back, what does that look
like? So, and that's kind of how we how
we approach it. and you kind of I'm
curious about your process like you know
when when you guys have a guy high on
your board but maybe you might I don't
know how you guys view other I don't
know how you find out what other teams
are thinking or what other
>> we can't call them and ask them what
they're doing.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So like but like how
do how do you you see like a lot of
people think this person might be lower
but we have this guy higher. How do you
determine whether okay we want to take a
chance here even though other people
could believe he might be lower? How do
you make
>> Yeah, I think the beauty of all this,
everybody kind of has their own board.
So, you have your grades, you're
probably not grading all the players the
same way. I think when you go through
this third round, I mean, the reality
is, I mean, they were basically coming
out of the woodwork in this p this last
round. So, there's a lot of players that
got drafted where you're looking up
there going, "Oh, okay. Probably
wouldn't have taken that that player.
Hey, maybe there's a few players. Oh, we
would consider him." So, we just kind of
go through our process, grade the
players, and create kind of categories
and buckets of players. All right, at
this pick. All right, here's three or
four names. All right, we're comfortable
picking one of them. All right, if you
move back and still get one of them, are
we good with that? Or would we rather
move? And I'd say in Cadence's case,
hey, let's move up a little bit because
there's a player that we sort of
identified. Look, what other teams are
going to do? Like honestly, like for
somebody to sit here and tell you like,
yeah, they knew what they were going to
do. I mean, they're lying. I'm not going
to tell you that. I mean, you're trying
to project to some degree. That's why we
go through the pro staff does an
incredible job of like looking at the
team. Hey, here's what we think their
needs are. What we think their needs are
might be different from what that team's
needs to what they think they are. So,
look, this is a big puzzle. You're
trying to piece it together. There's
probably a thousand pieces. Um, and
there's never one particular piece that
ultimately is going to be the deciding
factor, the driving force.
>> You guys have moved up twice already in
this draft, and it's because of the
aggressiveness that you you've targeted
players that you really like. When it
comes to day three, do you feel like
that because if you mentioned that picks
at 91, they may be the same players that
you're targeting around 96. Is it easier
or a little bit more challenging to get
aggressive for guys on day three?
>> It doesn't change. And again, I'm not
trying to minimize like moving, but like
moving two spots in our mind is
basically nothing. Like we don't view it
that way. I think when you start moving
8 to 10 spots, that's a little bit more
of a probably a calculated move where
you're probably going to have to give up
a little bit more capital. Um I would
say again, this is just how we view it.
You moving two spots and repositioning
picks, you don't really give anything up
other than draft slots. So again, yeah,
we moved up a few spots. Is that us
being aggressive? No, I think it's more
of us just sort of being strategic about
like what we feel like makes the most
sense and what we need to do. when
you're making a big jump, I would put
the, you know, look, I would put the
will move into that was an aggressive
move because we moved like a significant
amount of spots, moving two to three
spots, it's just more about positioning.
That's kind of how we talk about it as a
staff. Um, and it' be the same thing
tomorrow. So, we're 106, you like, does
it make sense to move a couple spots?
Then it's like, all right, how do we
reconstitute those picks? So I think
it'll be the same thought process
tomorrow as it's been the the past few
days.
>> There was something a little different
the other day that kind of predict your
answer on this one. Did anyone call you
about Nico Collins and was that just
something kind of random or not? It's
not not anything to that. And why would
you want to trade Nico Collins if
someone did want to call and talk about
that hypothetically?
>> Yeah, I mean look, teams call teams all
the time and ask about players. I mean
we're not trading Nico Collins. So, I
mean, like whoever reported it or
whatever information that they had, I
mean, I mean, they could take it and
shove it. Like, we're not trading Nico.
>> Obviously, you know, past few years,
teams have defense have kind of
countered the explosive passing attack,
playing more two shells, and obviously
offenses have kind of countered that by
trying to run more downhill. So, did did
that kind of help and I want to say
elevate McDonald's value knowing that
how teams want to play now, how um well,
teams want to attack you guys
specifically. Um knowing to have a guy
like that um that can I guess, you know,
in a sense be so good at stopping the
run when teams are trying to play more
to high safety looks and have those guys
in the middle to be able to counter
that.
>> I think our mentality on defense is to
play fast, violent, and physical. So,
who are the players that have those
qualities? Then forget about scheme,
forget about what other teams are doing.
Start with that premise. Fill the
players in. And then whoever we play
each week, it's going to be the same
thing. Like, we're going have to be good
in the running game. We're have to
minimize big plays. And we're going to
have to play well in the red area. And
defense is about points. The red area is
about points. So, it's it's more of the,
hey, here's what we want our defense to
be about. Here are the things that we
emphasize. All right. Who are those
players that actually fit? Like we pride
ourselves in being physical. Um, and
that's not going to change. I mean, as
long as Demo is the head coach, as long
as we're here running the team, we're
going to prioritize toughness and
physicality. So, let's find the players
that have those attributes. And if you
you want to be a big, strong, tough,
physical team. You better have big,
strong, tough, physical players that
enable you to play a certain way because
in the end, that's what wins in this
league.
>> All right. Thank you. Yep. Thanks.